A. Hyatt Mayor Papers
A. Hyatt Mayor Papers
1904-1946
Mayor, A. Hyatt (Alpheus Hyatt), 1901-1980.
1.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, 1904-1946; photographs, juvenilia, and printed material. Correspondence includes that of Anna Hyatt Huntington, Audella Hyatt, Leon Kroll, Alfred G. Mayor, and Harriet Randolph Hyatt Mayor.
149457
Biographical History
A. Hyatt Mayor was born in Gloucester, Mass. on June 28, 1901. In his early years he traveled to Europe with his mother, Harriet Hyatt Mayor and spent some time at his father's experimental marine biology station at Dry Tortuga, Florida. He graduated from Princeton University in 1922 and after teaching art history for a year at Vassar, he went on to do graduate work at Oxford as a Rhodes Scholar, after traveling extensively in Europe during the rest of the 1920s.
After working on several New York magazines, Hyatt Mayor joined the staff of Metropolitan Museum in the department of prints in 1932. The same year he married the former Virginia Sluder of St. Louis. In 1946 he was made curator of prints at the Metropolitan and held that position until his retirement. He had two children Alfred and Martha.
Mr. Mayor also served as a trustee of the American Federation of Arts and of Brookgreen Gardens in South Carolina. He was president of the Hispanic Society of America from 1955 until his death in 1980. He wrote several books and articles.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The A. Hyatt Mayor Papers covers more than forty years and comprises five series. They include correspondence, photos, childhood manuscripts, as well as journals of travels in Italy, Greece, and Egypt in the 1920's, and published materials including articles and newspaper clippings by and about Mr. Mayor and others.
Correspondence, includes incoming, outgoing, and correspondence to and from others. Subject File, contains book labels, a passport, photos, a program, and a book of photographs titled "Athens, 1927-1928". Manuscripts, consists of childhood school papers and sketches, journals, and copies of journal-letters from A. Hyatt Mayor's travels abroad, 1925-1927, a translation and other related items. Published Material, includes articles about others, and newspaper clippings about A. Hyatt Mayor and others. Oversize, consists of two photographs of Mr. Mayor which are located at the end of the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence are arranged alphabetically by author and Subject Files, Manuscripts, and Published Materials are arranged alphabetically by type. Oversize items are located at the end of the collection.
Related Material
The has numerous collections for the Hyatt-Mayor families. For information on members of the Hyatt, Mayor, Beebe, and Huntington families see for the finding aids of individual family members.
Subject and Genre Headings
Hyatt, Audella, 1840-1932.; Huntington, Anna Hyatt, 1876-1973.; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974.; Mayor, A. Hyatt (Alpheus Hyatt), 1901-1980.; Mayor, Alfred Goldsborough, 1868-1922.; Mayor, Harriet Randolph Hyatt, 1868-1960.; Hyatt family.; Mayor family.; Art historians -- United States.; Art museum curators -- United States.; Articles.; Bookplates.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Manuscripts (document genre); Passports.; Photograph albums.; Photographs.; Poetry.; Sketches.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - B - D (Box 1)
    - I, J - K (Box 1)
    - Huntington, Anna Hyatt (Box 1)
    - Hyatt, Audella
      - 1906-1907, 1909 (Box 1)
      - 1912-1913 (Box 1)
      - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
      - 1917-1918 (Box 1)
      - 1919-1920 (Box 1)
      - 1921-1923 (Box 1)
      - 1927-1928 (Box 2)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 2)
      - Undated (Box 2)
    - Kroll, Leon (Box 2)
    - L - M (Box 2)
    - Mayor, Alfred G.
      - 1904-1907 (Box 2)
      - 1909-1911, 1913-1914, 1917, 1922 (Box 2)
      - Undated (Box 2)
    - Mayor, Barbara, (later B. M. Money) (Box 2)
    - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt (Box 2)
    - Mayor, Virginia Sluder (Box 2)
    - O - S (Box 2)
    - V - W (Box 2)
    - Unidentified (Box 2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - 1912 (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence to and from others (Box 2)
- Subject File
  - Book Labels (Box 3)
  - Greek Passport, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Photograph Book
    - "Athens, 1927-1928" (Box 3)
  - Program, Undated (Box 3)
- Manuscripts
  - Childhood School Papers (Box 3)
  - Childhood Sketches (Box 3)
  - Composition and Poetry Book, holograph (Box 3)
  - Journal
    - "I Tatti Provence Burgundy", ca. 1925 (Box 3)
    - Egypt and Greece, 1927 (Box 3)
    - Letters, 1926-1927; Copies of various pages (no original); copied by Audella Hyatt (Box 3)
  - Translation of "Politics" by Jacinto Benavente (Box 3)
  - Sketch by "Virginia (Box 3)
  - Unidentified (Box 3)
- Published Materials
  - Article by (Box 3)
  - Article about, 8 May 1939 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - About A. Hyatt Mayor (Box 3)
    - About Others (Box 3)
- Oversize
  - Two photographs (Box 3)